{"tossups": [{"question": "Klemens von Galen spoke out against this program after a papal declaration opposing this program went partially ignored. Participants in this program later helped run Operation Reinhardt. Karl Brandt approved a petition for Gerhard Krechtsmar to be first victim of this program. Victims of this program were held at places like Grafeneck and Hartheim, where this program developed murder by gassing. Psychiatric hospitals were the primary site of, for ten points, what program that ordered \u201cmercy killings\u201dof the disabled in Nazi Germany?", "answer": "Aktion<b> T4</b> (or the<b> T4</b> Program)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The name of this group was derived from a Virginia county. The name \u2018Samuel\u2019 was used by two of this group\u2019s major figures, Abraham Woodhull and Robert Townsend. Information from this group led Rochambeau to deter a surprise attack at Newport, Rhode Island. \u2018John Bolton\u2019 was the alias of Benjamin Tallmadge, an American major who assembled this group on the orders of George Washington. For ten points, identify this group that discovered the treason of Benedict Arnold, an early American espionage ring.", "answer": "<b> Culper</b> Ring", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Philip Zelikow alleged that the U.S. government threatened to destroy works he wrote in opposition to these items. One document written by Alberto Gonzalez in this set claimed that the Geneva Convention could not be extended to stateless entities like the Taliban. John Yoo was once wanted for \u201ccrimes against humanity\u201d for his role in drafting these documents. For ten points, what set of 2002 documents advised the CIA on the use of \u201cenhanced interrogation techniques\u201d on U.S.-held detainees?", "answer": "<b> Torture Memos</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A lover of this man founded Enough is Enough, an organization opposed to online pornography. Tom Fiedler wrote a scandalous Miami Herald piece about this politician after getting a tip from designer Donna Weems. This man managed George McGovern\u2019s unsuccessful 1972 campaign and was targeted by Walter Mondale with the \u201cWhere\u2019s the Beef?\u201d ads. After a photo of this politician aboard the<em> Monkey</em> <em>Business</em> surfaced, this politician admitted to having an affair with Donna Rice. For ten points, name this\u201cfrontrunner\u201d Colorado Senator whose 1988 Democratic presidential campaign fell apart.", "answer": "Gary Warren<b> Hart</b> (accept Gary Warren<b> Hartpence</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The first media accounts of this event were based on telegraphs from the steamer<em> Platte Valley</em>, which was carrying survivors of this event. During this event one person was fastened to a tent with nails and lit on fire. General Grant claimed a report of this event left out \u201cthe part that shocks humanity to read.\u201dAttackers in this event cried \u201cNo quarter!, No Quarter!\u201d while shooting soldiers running from a bluff after they surrendered. For ten points, name this 1864 massacre of African American Union soldiers that Nathan Bedford Forrest may have ordered.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Fort Pillow</b> (or<b> Fort Pillow</b> Massacre)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 1970, this singer noted that even though she didn\u2019t \u201cbelieve in communism,\u201d she would post up to a quarter million dollars, if necessary, for bail for Angela Davis. This singer\u2019s 100th charting R&B single was a 2014 cover of Adele\u2019s \u201cRolling in the Deep.\u201d In 1972, director Sydney Pollack shot film of this singer recording a live album in Los Angeles; her ensuing album,<em> Amazing Grace</em>, became the highest-selling gospel album of all time, but the film of the same name wasn\u2019t released until 2018, three months after this singer\u2019s death and funeral in Detroit. For ten points, name this singer of \u201cChain of Fools\u201d and \u201cRespect,\u201dthe legendary \u201cQueen of Soul.\u201d", "answer": "Aretha<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "This structure\u2019s namesake path includes the peak of Black Mountain on Hatterall Ridge. Tintern Abbey overlooks this structure, which runs through much of the Wye Valley and the Shropshire Hills. Historians have speculated that this earthwork project was an attempt to intimidate the neighboring Kingdom of Powys by an 8th century king who conquered Northumbria. For ten points, name this trench dug by a Mercian king.", "answer": "<b> Offa\u2019s Dyke</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Playwright and ambassador Alexander Griboyedov was assassinated during a massacre in this empire after two Armenian women escaped. Paul Julius von Reuter, the founder of Reuters news, took control of customs incomes under this empire\u2019s ruler Naser-al-Din, during whose rule tobacco was deemed haram by an Ayatollah. This empire signed the humiliating Treaties of Gulistan and Turkmenchay, granting its Armenian land to Russia. Facing the Persian Constitutional Revolution, this empire was succeeded by Reza Khan of the Pahlavis. For ten points, name this Iranian empire that lasted from 1789 to 1925.", "answer": "<b> Qajar</b> Empire (accept<b> Sublime State of Persia</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This writer proposed a patriotic voluntary tax in a<em> Letter to the People</em> and received death threats for her abolitionist play,<em> The Slavery of the Blacks</em>. This writer wrote \u201cMan, are you capable of being fair...what gave you the sovereign right to oppress my sex?\u201d in a work which criticized the French Revolution\u2019s lack of gender equality and mimicked an earlier work drafted by the Marquis de Lafayette. For ten points, name this author of<em> The Declaration of the Rights of Woman and the Female Citizen</em>.", "answer": "Olympe<b> de Gouges</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s son was allowed to remain in power during a transition period in the Sun City Agreement. Many posters supported this man by noting, \u201cHere is the man we needed\u201d. Eddy Kapend was executed for a plot to kill this man, and his advisor Emmanuel Dungia was accused of trying to overthrow his son. Che Guevara decided this man was \u201cnot the man of the hour\u201d for being too distracted, but this man also had \u201cgenuine qualities of a mass leader\u201d. This man led a Marxist mini-state in South Kivu. Overthrowing Mobutu Sese Seko, for ten points, name this Congolese leader of the D.R.C.", "answer": "Laurent-D\u00b4esir\u00b4e<b> Kabila</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In this body of water, James George Meads founded the Republic of Morac-Songhrati-Meads, whose rival was the Kingdom of Humanity. The PLAN 314 propaganda documentary depicts one side\u2019s victory in this body of water at the Johnson South Reef. Reclamation projects in this region have been termed the Great Wall of Sand and include runways constructed on Mischief Reef. The Nine Dotted Line splits this body of water, containing the heavily contested Spratly and Paracel Islands. For ten points, name this sea that Vietnam, China and the Philippines all claim.", "answer": "<b> South China</b> Sea", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In this work. a pirate who attaches bells to his clothing terrorizes the Ba Commandery. An extremely fast horse in this book refuses to eat and starves to death after its original owner is killed. This book includes a scene in which a man becomes trapped in the Stone Sentinel Maze. A general in this work convinces his enemies that he can perform magic by praying to an alter for three days until a southeasterly wind appears. For ten points, name this book where a Sun Quan-Liu Bei alliance defeats Cao Cao at Red Cliffs, a classic novel by Luo Guanzhong.", "answer": "<b> Romance of the Three Kingdoms</b> (accept<b> Sanguo Yanyi</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "One branch of this dynasty ruled the Empire of Trebizond, and a famous mosaic depicts one member of this dynasty with his wife Irene of Hungary. A member of this dynasty glorified the deeds of her father in a history known as<em> The Alexiad</em>. The member of this dynasty described in that history invited the soldiers of the First Crusade to help him retake land in Asia Minor. For ten points, name this Byzantine dynasty that led a \u201crestoration\u201d under emperors like Alexios and Manuel I.", "answer": "<b> Komnenian</b> Dynasty (accept<b> Komnenos</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A cartoon referencing this man\u2019s death shows his shadow forming the word for woman,</b> <b>representing his love for carnal pleasures. Yale Professor George (+)</b> <b>Trumbull Ladd was</b> <b>invited by this man to serve as a diplomatic advisor. The assassin of this man gave 15 reasons why he killed this man at Harbin Railway Station. That assassin was An Jung-geun, a Korean independence activist who was enraged by the (*)</b> Eulsa Treaty. While meeting with Vladimir Kokovtsov, this Resident-General of Korea was killed. The Rikken Seiyukai party was created by this leader, who oversaw the signing of the Treaty of Shiminoseki. For ten points, name this first Prime Minister of Japan.", "answer": "<b> Ito</b> Hirobumi (accept<b> Hayashi</b> Risuke; accept<b> Hirofumi</b>; accept<b> Hakubun</b>; accept<b> Ito </b>Shunsuke)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Two unexpected strangers celebrated the 7th Birthday of this dynasty\u2019s namesake\u2019s son granting that founder a spell making his cellar always full. Besides a man named the (+)\u201cWheelright\u201d, another leader of this dynasty expanded church rights in the Congress of Cienia and was given the epithet \u201cSpindleshanks\u201d. The last king of this dynasty was the son of (*)</b> Wladyslaw the Elbow High and that \u201cPeasants King\u201d confirmed rights given to Jews granted by Boleslaw the Chaste. Casimir III the Great ruled this dynasty, whose first duke was Mieszko I. For ten points, name this ruling dynasty of Poland.", "answer": "<b> Piast</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This group carried out the Freeman Field Mutiny. Publicity for this group grew after Eleanor Roosevelt met with instructor Alfred \u201cChief\u201d Anderson, and one of its members,</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Benjamin O. Davis, would become a four star general. The nickname \u201cRed Tails\u201d</b> <b>referred to this group, whose existence was secured by an amendment that Harry (*) </b>Schwartz passed. Members of this group who trained at Moton Field formed the 332nd Fighter and 477th Bombardment groups. Often surrounded by a myth that they never lost a bomber, for ten points, name this group of African American pilots in World War II.", "answer": "<b> Tuskegee</b> Airmen", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One of these contracts was held by Joseph Coymans, who promised to send ten Capuchin monks to Africa. These short term contracts were contrasted with long term debt, or juros,</b> <b>as a method of raising revenue. Following the 1713 Treaty of (+)</b> <b>Utrecht, the South Sea</b> <b>Company earned the ability to carry out this monopoly. (*)</b> Enslaved Africans were brought to certain non-English New World colonies via these contract. Spain had an official monopoly on, for ten points, what contracts that allowed certain companies the right to transport slaves across the Atlantic.", "answer": "<b> Asiento</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One man from this family failed to create a farming community of Quakers at a location originally to be called \u201cColumbus\u201d and additionally built a replica of the Stonehenge there to remember World War I dead. A Museum at Maryhill, Washington, dedicated by (+) Queen Marie of Romania, was built by a member of this family who built the Peace Arch with Canada. Along with Samuel, another member of this family built a (*)</b> railway from Saint Paul to Seattle,. That man\u2019s railway merged with the Northern Pacific to create Burlington Northern. For ten points, name this family whose member James became known as \u201cThe Empire Builder\u201d for his Great Northern Railway.", "answer": "<b> Hill</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Tang Meng discovered that Medlar Fruit sauce used in this kingdom was imported by the Shu Commandery along the Zangke River. Empress Lu Zhi killed many extended family</b> <b>members of a ruler of this kingdom, though (+)</b> <b>Liu Heng would be more conciliatory</b> <b>towards this kingdom. Wu Di invaded this kingdom, then under Zhao Jiande, in 111, leading it to be annexed by the Han Dynasty. Considered to be part of the Trieu Dyansty, (*)</b> Zhao Mo of this kingdom was known for his tomb in Guangzhou, which contained a jade burial suit with red silk connecting the jade pieces. Annexing the Fujianese kingdom of Minyue, this kingdom was centered in Panyu. For ten points, name this southern kingdom in China consisting of the Yue People.", "answer": "<b> Nanyue</b> (accept<b> Nam Viet</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The phrase that names this concept was first introduced by Antoine Augustin Cournot, who thought it represented \u201cperfection.\u201d Hegel claimed that this concept would be achieved by the guidance of geist, or spirit. In one (+) grand narrative, proletariat class struggle will result in this concept in the form of a communist society. One work titled after this concept argues that it occurred after the fall of the (*)</b> Soviet Union and is represented by the long-term perpetual triumph of liberal democracy and capitalism. Marxist teleology ends in, for ten points, what concept, the point at which society stops progressing, which was written about by Francis Fukuyama?", "answer": "The<b> end of history</b> (accept<b> history</b> or<b> progress of history</b> until \u201ccommunist,\u201d prompt on\u201cteleology\u201d before mention) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>With the future first prime minister of his country, this man was expelled for</b> <b>refusing to reveal who wrote the article \u201cHell Hound at Large\u201d. This man was part of</b> <b>the Thirty Comrades and he led a revolt that led to (+) \u201cArmed Forces Day\u201d in his</b> <b>nation. For fighting against the allies, Winston Churchill called this man a \u201ctraitor</b> <b>rebel leader\u201d, and this man worked with Karen leaders at the (*)</b> Panglong Conference. Ba Win and this leader were killed by a paramilitary under U Saw. For ten points, name this father of a female Nobel Peace prize winner and current leader of Myanmar. ANSWER:<b> Aung San</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}